# **SAM AUBER**

dicemaster5.github.io/website

in linkedin.com/in/sam-auber

samauber@yahoo.co.uk

Game developer and digital artist with a passion for creating unique player experiences through immersive and artistic environments.

With over six years of experience in various aspects of game development with a focus in programming and tech art.

Worked with a variety of teams, from small indie groups to a large studio managing big IPs.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Lead Programmer on Townbox / VideoDojo Games

JANURARY 2024 - PRESENT / Part-time Freelance, remote

- Ownership and responsibility of core tech and code base architecture
- · Project features and milestone planning
- Major refactoring and rewriting of existing core systems
- Working alongside the creative director to ensure goals are me

# Software Engineer on Sonic Forces / SEGA HARDlight

AUGUST 2022 - FEBURARY 2024 / Full-time, Leamington Spa, England

- Collaborated with artists and designers on the development of multiple new characters and power-ups for Sonic Forces
- Developed a character editing and implementation tool for designers and artists to use when creating new characters for Sonic Forces
- Improved and worked on IAP features to generate more revenue
- Fixed and improved key areas within the Sonic Forces codebase

## Game Developer / Spelkollektivet

APRIL 2021 - JULY 2022 / Full-time Freelance, Sweden

- Led a team to develop a game prototype in 4 months that was demonstrated at a convention in Poland: Poznań Games Arena
- Developed solutions for rendering bottlenecks in Unity to improve frame rate
- Designed unique visual art styles for projects by coordinating closely with artists and developing shaders using HLSL and shader graph
- Created a procedural bipedal animation system in Unity for characters that I designed, modelled, textured and rigged with Blender

# Gameplay Programmer on Ruff 'N' Tumble / Psycho Hound

MARCH 2021 - APRIL 2021 / Full-time Freelance, remote

- Collaborated with the lead programmer to add core gameplay features such as the the pickup system and the use of weapons
- Optimised and improved existing gameplay features and systems
- Worked with colleagues to test and and troubleshoot gameplay features

#### **LANGUAGES**

**English:** Native

French: Fluent

#### **SKILLS**

### Programming:

- C# games ranging from prototypes to fully released
- C++ prototypes using SDL2 and OpenGL
- Python applications and games using Pygame and PyQt5 frameworks
- Javascript game server features and general web dev

#### Miscellaneous:

Agile/Scrum, 3D modelling, Web development, Graphic design

#### **TOOLS**

Unity, Godot, Unreal Photoshop, Illustrator, Figma Blender, Substance Painter Perforce, Git, GitHub Visual Studio, VSCode, Rider

## **EDUCATION**

2020 | BSc Hons | First Class Honours

Computing for Games

FALMOUTH UNIVERSITY

2016 | BTEC IVI3 | Triple Distinction\*
Interactive Media
BRISTOL COLLEGE GREEN